 Java Intro- https://www.oracle.com/technetwork/java/intro-141325.html
 Features of Java:-
    - Object Oriented
    - robust
    - secure
    - platform independent
    - high performing
    - interpreted
    - threaded
    - dynamic
 
Java platform:
    > Two Components:
        - Java Virtual Machine JVM
        - Java API

        -- both together known as JRE
    
    > Java Source Code is compiled as well as interpreted
        - Java compiler compiles source code to bytecode(intermediate code)
          that is interpreted by JVM into machine code and that is run on actual platform.
    *FLOW: Java Application Code --> Java Compiler --> ByteCode --> JVM --> Machine Code --> Run in Hardware OS 

Version and Editions:
    - Java EE
        - Java SE
            -Java ME

Object Oriented Programming

 - Class : Blueprint
 - Objects : Real world entities

 Features:
  - Abstraction
  - Inheritance
  - Polymorphism
  

  Primitive Data Types
    - byte 
    - short
    - int 
    - long
    - float
    - double
    - char
    - boolean

Objects v/s Primitive
 - Objects have state and behavior
 - Primitives have only single value

Instantiating an Object
    String s = new String();
    Circle c = new Circle();

    Circle = Reference Types
    c = reference variable
    new = keyword
    Circle() = Object type

Memory Management - Stack and Heap
    - In the memory managed by JVM behind the scenes,
         object references and objects assigned to them are managed by Stacks and Heaps

Objects contain data, data is stored in instance variables

Instantiating of an Object:
    - Using new keyword
    - When you Instance an Object with new Keyword you are actually re-creating a special method called Constructor
    
    Class X Instantiates Point
    Point point = new Point(2, 5);

    Class Point 
    public Class Point{
        //Constructor
         public Point(int p1, int p2){
             x = p1;
             y = p2;
         }
     }

Constructor gives you flexibility to pass any no. of parameters in int

Customer c = new Customer(a, b, c)
Customer c = new Customer();
Customer c = new Customer(a, b);

-> Creating Object Types
    - An object type is called as Class
    - A class is a template for object creation
    - An object is really an instance of class
    - Many object instances can be generated from the class

    Note: Each file may only contain only one public top level class
        * Other top level classes may be included in one file but they may not list an access modifier.(Encapsulation ref*)
        //Good Exam Topic
        public class HelloWorld{

        }
        class AHelperClass{

        }

        (Refer Car Class Example)

        - Instance Variables are created before methods in Class.
        
        
	"Void"
	A method that declares a return type of void cannot return any value.  So, for example, the following is illegal and would not compile:
	public void doSomething() {
	    return "Hello!";
	}
	
	It is, however, legal (though uncommon) to just use the return statement.
	public void doSomething() {
	    return;
	}
	
	
As mentioned, it's pretty uncommon (and useless) 
to see a return like that on it's own... though it can be used to end a method inside of a control structure.

-> Building Constructors

	    - Constructors are special methods
	    - Constructor methods have the same name as the class itself
	    - Constructor look just like other methods but they have no return types not even void
	    - Constructors are invoked only by using the new keyword not the dot notation like methods
	    - You should use Constructors to initialize data
	
	public class Car{
	    String color;
	    String type;
	
	    Car(String c, String t){
	        color = c;
	        type = t;
	    }
	}
	
	Car car = new Car ("blue", "Lambhorghini")

Q:  What's the difference between a "default" and a "no-arg" constructor?

	A:  A "no-arg" constructor is one that lists no parameters (it takes no arguments).  A "default" 
	    constructor is a "no-arg" constructor that is created by the compiler, 
	    in the event that you don't explicitly create one yourself.

-> Initialization Blocks
{
    //innitialization bock
}

//Example
//Initialization Block Example
	public Class Ib{
	
	    String a = "A for apple";
	
	    {
	        a = "A for Airplane";
	    }
	
	    Ib (){
	        a = "A for Air"; 
	        a
	    }
	}
	
	//a is assigned "A for Apple" first then "A for Airplane" and then "A for Air"
	
	public Class Ib{
	
	    {
	        a = "A for Airplane";
	    }
	
	    String a = "A for apple";
	    String b = "B for ball";    
	
	    Ib (){
	        a = "A for Air"; 
	        
	    }
	}
	
	//a is assigned "A for Apple" first then "A for Airplane" and then "A for Air"
	
	public Class Ib{
	
	    Ib (){
	        a = "A for Air";
	    }  
	    
	    String a = "A for apple";
	    String b = "B for ball";
	    
	    {
	        a = "A for Airplane";
	    }
	}
	
	//a is assigned "A for Apple" first then "A for Airplane" and then "A for Air"
	
	
	
	*************** SECTION 4: Static, Scope and Garbage Collection ***************
	
	***********Static Variables ************	
	- Data associated with the class instead of the object is stored in class variables(versus instance variables for objects or instances)
	- Class variables are also called static variables
	- They are called Static variables because the static keyword is used to identify them
	
	- TO access the static variable you use the name of the class and the class variable name
			public class Car{
				static int carCount;
				Car.carCount = 1;
				}
				
	- Oddly, you can use either the class name (Car) or the object reference of that type to access class variables
	
			Car myCar = new Car('Black', 'Ranger');
			myCar.carCount = 1;
			

	******************Static Methods*******************
	
	- A static method just like the static variables is associate with the class and not the objects(instances)
	- Static methods are called class methods
	- To call a non-static method that is instance you can call via class object.
	- But to call class methods that is static method
	
	static void resetCarCount(){
		carCount = 0;
		//resets car count to 0
		
	}
	
	Now to call class/static method you can just use class name
	
	Car c = new Car();
	c.resetCarCount(); //Legal but confusing
	Car.resetCount(); //Proper way to call class/static methods
	
	
	- Static methods do have access to any instance or object data
	carCount++;
		 serialNumber = carCount;
		 
		 color = "blue" //wrong as color is the instance variable
		 
		 
  Q: What is the point of using static methods???
  A: They generally have two purpose:
  		1. They are used to access(update & fetch) class variables data
  			- Although this can be done by any instance of the class. It is considered more appropriate to use the class or static methods for this purpose
  			- 
  		2. Static methods provide functionality without the need for an object/instance 
  		 	- FOr ex: maths formulas are great reasons to have static methods
  		 	
  		 	
-> Static Reference variables and null!!!
  
  -If the reference variable you are working with has a null value
   (meaning it is not referring to an object), it's in a dangerous state. 
  - Specifically, if you access an instance member with it, you will see the dreaded "NullPointerException."
	This is an exception created by the JVM and unless special exception handling code is written, will result in your program quitting prematurely
  
			  //null pointer exception
			  public static void main(String[] args) {
			    String s = null;
			    s = s.toUpperCase(); // Oops! s is null! 
				}
			  
			  public static void main(String[] args) {
			    Math m = null;
			    double result = m.floor(28.15); // Confusing code, but it works.
				}
			
			//CORRECT WAY
			public static void main(String[] args) {
				    double result = Math.floor(28.15);
				}
				
				
->Static Initialization Block

	static{
	  //code
	}
	
	static initialization block will executed once only when object is initialized
	while regular initialization block is executed every time a object is initialized
	
	static initialization block cannot access instance variables like static methods 
	but it can access class/static variables
	
	
	
-> Example
		public class Person {
		    {
		        personCount = 10;
		    }
		    static {
		        personCount = 20;
		    }
		    private static int personCount = 1000;
		    {
		        personCount = 30;
		    }
		    static {
		        personCount = 40;
		    }
		    public static void main(String[] args) {
		       System.out.println(Person.personCount); // Line A 
		       Person p = new Person(); // Line B
		       System.out.println(Person.personCount); // Line C
		       Person.personCount = 100; // Line D 
		       p = new Person(); // Line E
		       System.out.println(Person.personCount); // Line F
		    }
		}
		When the program starts and this main method is kicked off, the Person class is loaded.  This, in turn, makes the static personCount variable available, with a default value of 0 (remember, all instance and static variables start with default values).
		Next all of the static initialization blocks, and the static variable's explicit initialization are executed in the order they are listed, from top to bottom.  Therefore, the personCount variable is set to 20, 1000, and finally 40.  So Line A prints "40."
		On Line B, an object is instantiated, so that causes the instance initialization blocks to be executed in the order they are listed, from top to bottom.  So now personCount is changed to 10 and finally 30.  Line C prints the value "30."
		Line D changes the personCount to 100, but Line E causes the instance initialization blocks to be executed again.  Therefore, the final value printed in Line F is, once again, "30."  So the answer to the quiz is: 
		//OUTPUT:
		40
		
		30
		
		30
		
		
************This variable ********************

The various usages of 'THIS' keyword in Java are as follows:

	It can be used to refer instance variable of current class
	It can be used to invoke or initiate current class constructor
	It can be passed as an argument in the method call
	It can be passed as argument in the constructor call
	It can be used to return the current class instance
	
	--check examples in code

*************SCOPE***************************

Variables and methods have certain range in which they exist and where they can accessed
	- and this concept here is called scope
	- there are different levels of scope
	- scope pertains to where data exists
	- scope can easily be identified with the curly brackets or code blocks
	
You have seen a number of different locations for variables so far:
	- inside of a class - //Instance Variables
	- inside of a class but declared as static - //Static variables
	- inside of a method (as parameters) -//SLocal Variables
	
Local variables are not always method variables:
	- Local variables can be inside for() loops, if() stmts, etc.
	- Sometimes variables are described a "most-local" or "local-most" , meaning that it is nearest variables of a given name regardless of scope.
	

***************Garbage Collection****************

The JRE manages memory for you!
	- you nevr have to destroy an object or manage the memory it uses
	- the JRE deletes the object when it determines that they are no longer used. This process is known as garbage collection.
	- JRE's GC periodically searches memory for free objects that are no longer needed
	- When it finds one, it removes from the Heap
	Example:
	
	Customer c = new Customer("ABCD");
	c = new Customer("XYZQ");//here the garbage collector will remove the memory for "ABCD" customer as it is no longer needed
	
     or 
     
    MyCar myCar = new MyCar();
    myCar = null;
    //so now the myCar object is eligible for Garbage collection
    
**************Java Memory Leaks*********************

A Memory Leak is a situation when there are objects present in the heap that are no longer used, but the garbage collector is unable to remove them from memory and, thus they are unnecessarily maintained. A memory leak is bad because it blocks memory resources and degrades system performance over time.
So sometimes you manually remove them like setting object as null
myCar = null;

**************Packages*********************
- Packaging is way to organize your class.
Uses of Packages:
	- makes it easier to use classes, interfaces, enums
	- avoids naming conflicts
	- help control access to code
- Think of package as code folder

The astrik * in the import can be used only to specify all the classees within a package.
import transport.A* // won;t compile
import.java.* //wont import anything
import.java.util.* //works

--you cannot use astrik with package stmt like "package com.abc.xyz.*" //won't copile

****************Primitive Data Types******************
- There are 8 primitive Data types:
	Integer types: byte, short, int, long
	Floating types: float, double
	Boolean types: boolean
	Character types: char
	
	Declaration: 
	byte b;
	char c;
	int a;
	
Boolean:
	1. can have either true or false. The values true and false are boolean literals
	2. boolean cannot be converted directly into any other types
	boolean b = true;
	if(b){
	//logic
	}else{
	//logic
	}
	
Character(1 bit) types:
	1. A character is a unicode text character
	2. To support unicode, the java character is 16 bits
	3. ASCII is a subset of unicode. The last 8 bits of unicode represent ASCII if the first 8 bits are 0
	There are three different types of character literals:
	1. The simple 'type' a is literal char in java
	2. The escape characters '\n', '\t', and '\\' are characters in java. These represent new line, tab and backslash.
	3. Hex notation can be used to represent characters that are not used in the keyboard
	4. The format is '\uXXXX' where he X's represnt hexadecimal numbers. This way you can assign all 16 bits of the char. 
	For ex: '\u0061' is the character 'a'

Integer Types:
	1. byte is 8 bits. In java it can hold from -2^2 to 2^7-1
	2. short is 16 bits. (-2^15 to 2^15-1)
	3. int is 32 bits. (-2^31 to 2^31-1)
	4. long is 64 bits (-2^63 t0 2^63-1)
	
	myInt = 070; //70 octal is 56 in decimal notation
	octal numbers start from 0
	Binary (in Java 7)
	int myInt = 0b101; //101 binary is 5 in decimal
	Underscores
	Also as of java 7, underscores can be used in numeric literals to help the readabilty of code
	Underscore help in readability of values
	int a = 1234567
	int a = 1_234_567
	
	int a = 30.210 //legal
	int a = 30._210 //illegal
	int a = 30.210_ //illegal
	int a = 30_.210 //illegal
	int a = 30_210.50 //legal
	
	**********************Primitive Conversion****************
	
    byte v =(int)50;
    
    *********************Operators, Loops and Syntax**************
    if else if
    switch case
    enums
    while loop
    do-while loop
    for loop
    labels
    break
    continue
    increment operator/decrement operator
    precedence operator
    
    check code for examples
    
    ******************* Strings*********************
    
  Strings are java objects
   String s = new String("Hello"); // new object is created in heap of array of chars everytime object is create referring to samr string
      or
   String s = "Hello"; //only once in heap
   
   Strings are immutable!
    - 	reassignment of String Object references creates a lot of "garbage objects"
    - This is why we can use StringBuilder and StringBuffer classes
    when an application needs to manipulate a lot of strings
    - StringBuilder and StringBuffer (both java.lang) provide a mutable
    sequence of characters but without the fancy String literals and Operators
    - StringBuffer is thread-safe whereas StringBuilder is not thread-safe! once in heap


  *******************Passing By Value********************
  
  - All the variables in Java are passed by Value
  - A primitive passed buy values means a copy of primitive is made
  - An Object passed by value means a copy of the reference is made
  - check PassbyValue.java example in project code
  
  **************Encapsulation / Data Hiding******************
  
  - Encapsulation and /or data hiding are terms in OOPS are often used interchangeably
  - Encapsulation s the technique of bundling data with methods that operate on that data
  - Data hiding is bundling classes such that direct access from an object's data is prohibited except through encapsulating methods
  - In Java, the modifiers public and private are most commonly used means to control access
  - With encapsulation/data hiding, data stored in the object is hidden or private while using public methods
  to manipulate the data
  
  GETTER and SETTERS
  
  In Java, getter and setter are two conventional methods that are used for retrieving and updating value of a variable.

The following code is an example of simple class with a private variable and a couple of getter/setter methods:

public class SimpleGetterAndSetter {
    private int number;
 
    public int getNumber() {
        return this.number;
    }
 
    public void setNumber(int num) {
        this.number = num;
    }
}
The class declares a private variable, number. Since number is private, code from outside this class cannot access the variable directly, like this:

SimpleGetterAndSetter obj = new SimpleGetterAndSetter();
obj.number = 10;    // compile error, since number is private
int num = obj.number; // same as above
Instead, the outside code have to invoke the getter, getNumber() and the setter, setNumber() in order to read or update the variable, for example:


SimpleGetterAndSetter obj = new SimpleGetterAndSetter();
 
obj.setNumber(10);  // OK
int num = obj.getNumber();  // fine

So, a setter is a method that updates value of a variable. And a getter is a method that reads value of a variable.

Getter and setter are also known as accessor and mutator in Java.

By using getter and setter, the programmer can control how his important variables are accessed and updated in a correct manner, 
such as changing value of a variable within a specified range. Consider the following code of a setter method:1

public void setNumber(int num) {
    if (num < 10 || num > 100) {
        throw new IllegalArgumentException();
    }
    this.number = num;
}
That ensures the value of number is always set between 10 and 100


ACCESS MODIFIERS

- PUBLIC
	- access is not limited
- PRIVATE
	- Access is only allowed by the declaring class
- PROTECTED
	- Access is allowed by the declaring class, any class in the same package, and any extending class(of any package)
- DEFAULT
  - Access is allowed by the declaring class and from any class in the same package
  
******************INHERITANCE************************
- Inheritance is best used for RE-usability of classes
- ALl methods and instance variables of the extended class are automatically the part of the class!
- Java is a single inheritance OOP Language, this means that in Java, each class can only extend one class

Super Class: The class whose features are inherited is known as super class(or a base class or a parent class).

Sub Class: The class that inherits the other class is known as sub class(or a derived class, extended class, or child class).
		   The subclass can add its own fields and methods in addition to the superclass fields and methods.
		   
Reusability: Inheritance supports the concept of �re-usability�, i.e. when we want to create a new class and there 
			is already a class that includes some of the code that we want, we can derive our new class from the existing class. 
			By doing this, we are reusing the fields and methods of the existing class.
			
Single Inheritance : In single inheritance, subclasses inherit the features of one superclass. In image below, the class A serves as a base class for the derived class

Multilevel Inheritance : In Multilevel Inheritance, a derived class will be inheriting a base class and as well as the derived class also act as the base class to other class.
 In below image, the class A serves as a base class for the derived class B, which in turn serves as a base class for the derived class C. In Java, a class cannot directly access the grandparent�s members.
			
			
Hierarchical Inheritance : In Hierarchical Inheritance, one class serves as a superclass (base class) for more than one sub class.In below image, the class A serves as a base class for the derived class B,C and D.

Multiple Inheritance (Through Interfaces) : In Multiple inheritance ,one class can have more than one superclass and inherit features from all parent classes. Please note that Java does not support multiple inheritance with classes.
					 In java, we can achieve multiple inheritance only through Interfaces. In image below, Class C is derived from interfaces
					 
Hybrid Inheritance(Through Interfaces) : It is a mix of two or more of the above types of inheritance. Since java doesn�t support multiple inheritance with classes, the hybrid inheritance is also not possible with classes.
						 In java, we can achieve hybrid inheritance only through Interfaces.

Using super() to chain child and Parent class constructors- 
I mentioned that when chaining constructors, the call to the super constructor must be the first statement in the constructor.  And that's true.  Assuming the Person class contains a no-arg constructor, the following constructor is valid:

public Employee() {
    super();
    deptId = 281;
}
...whereas this one is not:

public Employee() {
    deptId = 281;
    super();
}
I want to clarify that using super with the dot operator, to invoke a super type's method (other than a constructor) or access its state, is NOT bound by the first statement rule.

Both of these examples are valid:

public void driveLikeDad() {
    super.drive();
    doSomethingElse();
}

*****************Method Overloading*********************

- Java allows you to use same name for any number of methods
- this is called method overloading
- the signature must be unique, that the name and parameter(number & type) of method must be unique to do overloading
- return type of method does not make any different, only method name and params and params return type and params order\

below is unique
public static void sayHello(String fName. int age){...)
public static int sayHello(String lName){...}

below is unique
public static void sayHello(String fName. int age){...)
public static int sayHello(int age, String lName){..)

****************Method Overriding************************
- Overriding is changing the definition/functionality of a method a class inherits
- To override a method , the method must have the same signature
- In other words, the name and params of the the overriding method must be exactly the same as the overriden method
- If the method names are same but params are different then your overloading the method rather than overriding the method 
- You can override the parents class method

rules- 
 	- The return type must be the same or a subtype of the overridden return type
 	- An overriding method cannot be less accessible than the inherited method (same or more access modifier)
 	// wrong example
 	// the method drive in SOn class is not public and class son is less accessible too
 	public class Father {
 	 	public void driver(){...} 	
 	}
 	
 	class Son extends Father {
 		void drive(){...}
 	}
 	
 	// corrected example
 	public class Father {
 	 	public void driver(){...} 	
 	}
 	
 	public class Son extends Father {
 		public void drive(){...}
 	}
 	
 Rules of Overriding methods:
 
 - Overriding methods cannot declare additional exceptions than declared in the overridden method.
 UNLESS, the new exceptions are either a subtype of one of the overridden exceptions or is a "runtime" exception
 
 - static and private methods cannot be overridden (that is why father static is called in Tester example in code)

 - What if an instance of the Son wants or needs to drive like an instance of Father?
 	- The super keyword can also be used to call on the super class's method's
 	
 	class Son extends Father{
 	public void drive() {...}
 	public void driveLike Dad() {...}{
 	
 	super.drive(); / calls on the Father drive() method
 	}
 	
 	super.super..drive() is WRONG - you can only have one super!
 	
******************Covariant Returns****************
Consider a whosMyAncester() method below:
	public class GrandFatherRegistry{
		public GranFather whosMyAncester(String son) {...}
	}
	
- An Covariant return is where a subtype is listed in the place of the supertype
	- Overridden methods may use a covariant return
	- For Example, an overridden method may be declared a shown below:
	
	public class FatherRegistry extends GrandFatherRegistry{
		public Father whosMyAncester(String son) {...}
	}
	
- The primary reason for covariant returns is to allow a caller to epect a more
specific type of return than the one declared in the overridden method

	Father dad = fatherRegistry.whosMyAncester("111111")
	
	
****************************FINAL*******************************
The three faces of "final" 
	 - The modifier final means "unable to change"
	 - Final can be used for three different things:
	 	- Final before a variable makes the variable a constant
	 	- Final before a method makes it so the method cannot be overridden
	 	- Final before a class makes that class un-extendable
	 	
1. To create a constant, just add the final modifier when you declare a variable
	- final variables can be local(in a method) or a variable(static or instance) of a class
	- Constants are usually static
	- By convention, constant names are in upperclase. If needed, underscores are used to separate words
	- If you have a constant instance variable you can set the value for that constant in the constructor or with explicit initialization 
		example: 			 
		 	public class FinalTest {
		 		public static final int LESS_TRAVELED = 0; //explicit initialization
		 		public final int SHORTEST;
		 		public FinalTest() {
		 				SHORTEST = 1; //constructor initialization
		 			}
		 		}
	 - Final variables must be set before they are used
	 - Trying to set a final outside of explicit initialization or in a constructor results in a compiler error.
	 
	 	example:
		 	public class FinalTest {
		 		public static final int LESS_TRAVELED = 0; //explicit initialization
		 		public final int SHORTEST;
		 		public foo() {
		 				SHORTEST = 1; //COMPILE ERROR - cannot assign a value to final variable SHORTEST
		 			}
		 		}
		 		
2. When you place a final modifier in front of a method, that method can no longer be overriden.
		example:
			public class Father{
				public final void drive(){
					setVelocity(45);
					setPath(LESS_TRAVELLED);
					go();
				}
			}
			
			public class Son extends Father{
				public final void drive(){ //ILLEGAL!! Results in compile time error
					setVelocity(45);
					setPath(SHORTEST);
					go();
				}
			}
			
3. The last way to use the final modifier is to place it in front of a class
	- Placing final in front of a class indicates the class should have no descendants
	example:
			public class Father{
				public final void drive(){
					setVelocity(45);
					setPath(LESS_TRAVELLED);
					go();
				}
			}
			
			public class Son extends Father{ //ILLEGAL!! Results in compile time error
			.
			.
			.
			}
	
4. The string class is final. You cannot inherit from String and change its functionality

5. Java Enum constants are implemented as static and final

6. Switch case can use constants
		- Now that we've learned about "final," we can add constants to our short list of valid case values.  Constants works because their value is known at compile time.  So the following is legal:

		final char A_GRADE = 'A';
		final char B_GRADE = 'B';
		char studentGrade = 'A';
		switch (studentGrade) {
		    case A_GRADE:
		        System.out.println("Student received an A");
		        break;
		    case B_GRADE:
		        System.out.println("Student received a B");
		        break;
		    default:
		        System.out.println("Student received a C or lower");
		}
	 	
	 	
	 	

***********************POLYMORPHISM*********************
Polymorphism - many forms

- In programming, it means a class has the same interface or set of methods but different implementation
- In a word, polymorphism is about substitutability. 
- The principle provides OOP language like Java with extreme code flexibility.

 	
 Polymorphism is the ability for any one object to be referred by several different types of references.
 
 Example:
 
 Employee e = new Employee();
 Person p = e;
 //or all on single line
 Person p = new Employee();
 
 
 Person is reference type
 Employee() is the object type
 
 Person p = new Employee(); //is LEGAL
 
 As long as the Object type is a descendant of the reference type, this is legal
 
 Employee e = new Person(); //this is illegal
 //Person is not a descendant of Employee
 
 - Employee "is-a" Person, so it can be stored in a Person reference.
 
 	
Why use Polymorphism?

	- Polymorphism promotes flexibility and separation of concerns
	- The power of polymorphism ties into the concept of overriding methods
	
To see another example of polymorphism, examine the simplified Person and Employee class below:
	public class Person{
		String firstName;
		String lastName;
		public String getDescription(){
			System.out.println("In person");
			return firstName + " " + lastName;
			}
		}
		
	public class Employee extends Person{
		String title;
		public String getDescription(){
			System.out.println("In Employee");
				return super.getDescription() + : " + title;
		
		}
	
	}
	
	So, if we call like this in main:-
	
	Person p = new Employee();
	System.out.println(p.getDescription);
	
	- Infact the Employee's getDescription() method will be called ! The Person's getDescription() method is called only because of the super.getDescription() call
	- Assuming this Employee's name is "John Smith" and the title is "instructor", the following output would be result
	
	Output:-
	
	In Employee
	In Person
	John Smith Instructor
	
	- Even though the reference type is a Person, at runtime Java figures out which method is called based on the actual object type
	
 	*- This is known as "Dynamic Method Dispatching"
 	- When the code runs the virtual machine looks for a definition of getDescription() in the object first
 	- Then the virtual machine traverses up the inheritance tree looking for the method in question
 	- This is why final methods execute faster. 
 	- There is no need to figure out dynamically where a method is defined
    
At run =time a method call can be discovered, but at compile time the compiler
must know that each method and instance variable will be available at runtime. 

Person p = new Employee();
p.title = "Instructor"; // ILLEGAL ! title is not defined in Person

 - The above code is ILLEGAL
 - At runtime the JVM known that the Person variable (p) refers to an Employee object
 - However, at compile tie the java compiler does not know the real object type. It only knows "p" as a Person
 - Therefore, the compiler checks for title against the reference type. Since its not a part of Person it fails.

"being available to an object" is not the same as "being declared inside an object."  Let's say we have a subtype of Employee called Instructor.  If we create an Employee reference variable, we can call any member available to Employee - including those members it inherits.  For example:

Employee e = new Instructor();
e.setFirstName("Jane"); 
... is legal because Employee inherits the setFirstName method from Person.  It wasn't declared inside Employee, but it was available to Employee.
  So that's why I specifically say that a reference variable is limited to the members that are available to, rather than defined inside, the class itself.
			
			
			
*********************************Object Type Casting*******************

 - Casting in primitive data types is used to force truncation of larger types such as int into smaller types such as byte
 - With objects, casting is used to return an object to a more specific type
 
 Example
 
 Person p = new Employee();
 System.out.println(p.getdesc());
 Employee e (Employee) p;
 e.title = "Instructor"; // legal because title is defined in Employee
 
 - The typecast in this case is used to get functionality back into reference
 - A typecast can also be done without creating another reference as shown in the code below. This too, adds functionality back into the reference
 
 Person p = new Employee();
  System.out.println(p.getdesc());
  ((Employee) p).title = "Instructor";
  
  - Typecasting objects must handled with care, as it can be used incorrectly
  
  Person p = new Person();
  Employee e = (Employee) p; //compiles but fails at runtime
  
  - In the case above the compiler does not check the object type so it allows this misguided cast
  - at runtime this will fail, casting a Person object  to the EMployee type does not make sense
  - you cannot add functionality to an object that was not there to begin with
  - The above code will generate a ClassCasException.

  - To protect your casts at runtime use 'instanceOf' operator
  - 'instanceOf' is a boolean operator
  
  if(p instanceOf Employee){
  	  ((Employee) p).title = "Instructor";
  	 }
  		
  - The instanceOf operator can be used not only to cast appropriately but to execute code conditionally
  based on the type of market
  
  example:
  
  public class PayService {
  	public void cutCheck(Employee e){
  		double gross = e.pay();
  		if(!(e instanceOf Manager)){
  			...//award the special bonus
  			
  		}
  		...//do the work of paying an employee
  	}
  }
  
  ********************The Object Class*******************
  
  -> Two commonly overridden methods can further demonstrate polymorphism
  	- The method toString() is used to convert objects to Strings
  	- The method equals() is used to compare two objects
  	- Both toString() and equals() are originally defined in the class java.lang.objects
  	
  -> Everything in Java (except primitives) "is a" object literally! That is, every class in Java eventually
  extends java.lang.Object
  	- If you don't extend a class as your parent you automatically extend java.lang.Object
  	- Thus in the case of the Person class definition below 
  	
  	public class Person()
  		- this is same as below
  	public class Person() extends Object()
  	
  	- Therefore, every Java Object is an Object whether you like it or not
  	- every class inherits everything defined in objects
  	
  	
 *******************Abstract Classes***********************
 - Abstract classes allow a designer to generalize functionality of classes without providing implementation details
 - This is useful when capturing similarities between classes
 - take for example, the rectangle and the circle classes:
 	
 		public class Circle{
 			public double c;
 			public double area(){
 				return Math PI*r*r;
 			}	
 		}
 			
 		public class Rectangle{
 			public double h, w;
 			public double area(){
 				return h*w;
 			}
 		}
 		
 - Similarities such as the area() method, often indicate that classes like Rectangle and Circle should be related in some way
 - the similarity here can be Generalized in a Shape upper class
 - However , in doing so , you soon realize that there is no good way to define a generalized area method
 
 		public class Shape {
 			public double area() {...}
 		}
  
  // Circle extends Shape
  // Rectangle extends Shape
  
  - Java allows developers to leave the definition or implementation of method off.
  	- Use the abstract in front of the method name and include no code block to signify that the method is only a placeholder
  	- Abstract methods have no implementation
  	- Abstract methods cannot be instantiated, means no new w keyword
  	- Descendent classes of an abstract class must implement the inherited abstract methods or become abstract themselves
  	
  	
  	example:
  	
  		public abstract class Shape{
  			public abstract double area();	
  		}
  		
  	- Abstract classes can't be instantiated
  		
	  	new Shape(); //illegal
	- Abstract classes can contain non-abstract methods
	- Abstract classes are classes strictly designed to be extended	
	
	// Circle extends Shape
  	// Rectangle extends Shape
  	
  	IMP: certain modifiers, such as private, static, and final cannot be used on an abstract method.  
  	If you think about this logically, it makes sense.  Private, static, and/or final methods cannot be overridden, 
  	and all abstract methods must be overridden.  Therefore these modifiers cannot appear in an abstract method declaration.
	  	
  ************************************Interfaces*****************************
  An interface is a pseudo class
  - Interfaces are defined in their own file with a java extension
  - In this case, the interface would be found in a file called Drawable.java
  - In the definition, replace the class keyword with the interface keyword
  - Interfaces can only contain methods that are public and are one and only one of these types : abstract, default, or static
  - Since the public modifier is implied, sometimes it is not present in the declaration
  - Also, if the neither abstract, default, or static is listed in the declaration, it is set to abstract
  - In addition to methods, interfaces can only contain variables that are public, static and float.
  - these three modifiers are all implied, so they do not need to appear in the definition
 Abstract interface methods follow the same rules as abstract methods in abstract classes
  - Up until Java SE 8 this was the only type of method permitted in an interface
  - With the release of Java SE 8,default and static methods were added to the language 
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
				